TRAVIS **MALONEY**

226-688-7969 | travis.maloney1@gmail.com | travismaloney.com

Summary

Junior Web Developer with a background knowledge of Computer Science. Experience working independently to prioritize and track assignments and deadlines while interacting effectively with a team to achieve common objectives. Always maintain flexibility to adapt to changing environments while remaining focused on achieving desired results. Quick learner who is passionate about technology.

Education

Web Development Full-Time

Jan 2016- Mar 2016

Brainstation
Toronto, Ontario

Computer Science

May 2015 - Dec 2016

University of Western Ontario

London, Ontario

Completed 8 Computer Science courses towards a BSc. in Computer Science

Human Resources Management Graduate Certificate

2011-2012

Georgian College Barrie, Ontario

Bachelor of Management and Organizational Studies Specialization in Finance and Administration

2007-2011

University of Western Ontario London, Ontario

Work Experience

Sole Properietor/Developer

June 2017-Present

Forest City Digital Services, London, ON

- Created websites for small businesses, primarily utilizing HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and LESS/SASS. Git was used for version control and deployed to Digital Ocean Ubuntu VPS.
- Acted as a Development Contractor for RGB Digital Development. Developed a web app (user portal/social network) using MySQL, Node.js, React and Express. Git used for version control, deployed to a GoDaddy CentOS 6 VPS.

Customer Service Representative Financial Advisor

May 2015 – September 2016 January 2013 – May 2015

Scotiabank, London, ON

- Utilized critical thinking skills and available resources to address customer inquiries and provided value-added solutions in addition to assisting with clients' explicit needs
- Actively listened to clients and utilized tools to develop and implement financial planning strategies to efficiently and effectively meet clients' financial goals while maximizing customer profitability

TRAVIS **MALONEY**

226-688-7969 | travis.maloney1@gmail.com | travismaloney.com

Community Involvement

Hack Western Participant

2016/2017

University of Western Ontario, London, ON 2016 Winner of Organizing Team's Choice Award

Public Arts Commissioner

March 2010 - April 2011

University of Western Ontario, London, ON

- Aided the student life department in organizing, promoting, and maintaining a public art gallery
- Organized and executed Festival of the Arts, helping the University's Students' Council to achieve its goals of offering students engaging cultural programming

Assistant Head Soph/Society of Off Campus Students Coordinator

January 2010 – April 2011

University of Western Ontario, London, ON

- Built strong relationships with incoming students and aided them in their post-secondary success
- Facilitated training for over two hundred orientation week volunteers
- Underwent leadership and diversity training through the Student Success Centre and the University Students' Council
- Helped select and lead a team of 45 volunteers from 350 applicants

Peer Mentor, Leadership and Mentorship Program

September 2009 - April 2010

University of Western Ontario, London, ON

- Mentored and was a peer leader to 50 first year students
- Assisted first year students with their academics and transition to university
- Provided first year students with a variety of leadership opportunities and engaging programming

Courses

- COMPSCI 1026: Comp Sci Fundamentals I
- COMPSCI 1027: Comp Sci Fundamentals II
- COMPSCI 2208: Intro to Computer Organization and Architecture
- COMPSCI 2209: Applied Logic for Computer Science
- COMPSCI 2210: Data Structures and Algorithms
- COMPSCI 2211: Software Tools & Systems Programming
- COMPSCI 3319: Databases I
- COMPSCI 3357: Computer Networks I

Technologies

- Git, GitHub, Visual Studio Code, Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS), TDD (Mocha), gulp.js
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Sass
- Previously used (> 6 months ago): Java, Android Studio, Python, Flask, C, Eclipse